ALEX HARTER

IT Specialist

• Houston, TX (Wanting to Relocate to DFW)

@ alex.harter.tech

? AlexHarter

SUMMARY

Dedicated and versatile technology professional with experience in fintech, music, and education. Proven ability to quickly learn and apply a variety of technical skills combined with competent oral and written communication both as a leader and as part of a team. Passion for serving clients to solve technical problems effectively.

EXPERIENCE

Choral Music Specialist | November 2021 - Present

Self-Employed

- → Software Utilize publishing and audio software to create and transmit sheet music, service booklets, and recordings. Implemented morning service booklet which is now used every week.
- → Performance & Leadership Lead choirs in various services by singing, conducting, and giving directions in order to make services more orderly and encourage participation. Plan and lead rehearsals.

Data Automation Consultant | July 2022 - February 2023

Encapture | Dallas, TX

→ Data Extraction - Extracted client-requested information from received documents sorted

- in alexhartertech
- **(**940) 597-4771

by classification algorithms then validated and translated that data according to customer specifications.

- → Presentation Demoed in-progress pipelines to clients to present progress, ask questions, and teach how to interface with the products. Communicated internal software issues to the Product team with ideas for improvement for various clients.
- → Documentation Edited and contributed to documentation on Classification software for internal/client use.
- → Team-Building Started a book club with coworkers to improve professional and personal skills.

Choir Teacher / Special Education Paraprofessional | September 2019 -November 2021

Responsive Education Solutions | Founders Classical Academy of Corinth

EDUCATION

CompTIA A+ - Core 1 Passed; Core 2 In Progress

Post-Graduate Certificate in Data Science & Business Analytics | August 2023 - April 2024

University of Texas at Austin

→ Curriculum included Python; Data Analysis with Pandas; Data Visualization with Seaborn;

Statistics with NumPy; and Machine Learning with SciKit Learn

Texas Educator Content Certified in Music EC-12 & Special Education EC-12

Bachelor of Science in Rehabilitation Studies | Minor in Music | Cumulative GPA: 3.74

University of North Texas | Denton, TX | Graduated Magna Cum Laude December 2019

PROJECTS

GregoLy - for Cantatorium (in progress)

→ Python script to convert gabc files in Gregorian notation to LilyPond in modern notation

EasyVisa - for Data Science & Business Analytics Certificate

→ Jupyter notebook demonstrating bivariate data analysis and training machine learning models on structured data

Abridged Sunday Matins Booklet for St. Sophia Ukrainian Catholic Church

→ Morning service booklet including music adapted from Slavonic to English, currently used every week

SKILLS & INTERESTS

- → **Technical Skills:** Python, Linux, Linux, Git, Regular Expressions, Data Analysis, Machine Learning, Office Software, Publishing Software, Audio Software
- → Soft Skills: Agile, Getting Things Done, Personal Information Management, Project Management, Teamwork, Communication, Attention to Detail, Problem Solving, Customer Service
- → Interests: **②** Emacs, 🖽 Music Theory, 🏲 Karate